31st Annual Shuka Festival
‪‬
‪♪ ぜんぶ天気のせいでいいよ‬
We can blame it all on the weather
‪♪ この気まずさも&lrm;倦怠&lrm;感も‬
All this awkwardness and exhaustion
‪♪ 太陽は隠れながら知らんぷり‬
The sun hides away, pretending not to see
A packed train clatters along the track
‪♪ ガタゴト揺れる満員電車‬
‪♪ すれ違うのは準急列車‬
It brushes past a local express
I'm gonna search for feelings
in a shapeless cloud
‪♪ 輪郭のない雲の‬
‪　　　表情を探してみる‬
The test asks, "How was
the author feeling here?"
‪♪ 「作者の気持ちを答えなさい」‬
‪♪ いったいなにが‬
‪　　　　正解なんだい？‬
What could the right answer possibly be?
Breaking through the script
of pre-established harmony
‪♪ 予定調和の‬
‪　　　シナリオ踏み抜いて‬
Everyone talks about the
"springtime of life"
‪♪ 青い春なんてもんは‬
And I'm just not cut out for that
‪♪ 僕には似合わないんだ‬
Yet I know that this moment,
which will never come again,
‪♪ それでも知ってるから‬
‪　　　　一度しかない瞬間は‬
is rich with evanescence
‪♪ &lrm;儚&lrm;さを&lrm;孕&lrm;んでる‬
I will never forget, ever
‪♪ 絶対忘れてやらないよ‬
‪♪ いつか死ぬまで何回だって‬
So many times before I die someday...
‪♪ こんなこともあったって‬
‪　　　　　　　笑ってやんのさ‬
I'll laugh thinking about what it was like
I feel like the wind's leaving me behind
‪♪ 風においてかれそうで‬
So I'm desperately clinging on
‪♪ 必死に&lrm;喰&lrm;らいついてる‬
That familiar sound of the bell
Butler Cafe
‪♪ いつもの鐘の音も‬
‪　　　窓際に積んだ&lrm;埃&lrm;も‬
That dust piled up on the window sill
Even the smell of the classroom
‪♪ 教室の匂いだって‬
I will never forget, ever
‪♪ 絶対忘れてやらないよ‬
‪♪ いつか死ぬまで何回だって‬
So many times before I die someday...
I'll laugh thinking about what it was like
‪♪ こんなこともあったって‬
‪　　　　　　　笑ってやんのさ‬
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#12 Morning Light Falls on You
‪‬
Thank you!
‪ありがとうございました！‬
That was our first song,
"I Will Never Forget!"
‪１曲目“忘れてやらない”でした‬
I can't believe how enthusiastic they are.
‪意外と盛り上がった‬
‪喜多ちゃ～ん！‬
Kita-chan!
‪けど…‬
But...
You were so cute!
Now, before we play our next song...
‪それじゃあ 次の曲の前に‬
Let's have a few words from
Kessoku Band's leader:
‪結束バンドのリーダー‬
‪ドラムの伊地知虹夏先輩です‬
our drummer and my senpai, Nijika Ijichi!
‪‬
Nice to meet you, everyone!
‪皆さん はじめまして！‬
Are you having a good time?!
‪盛り上がってますか～？‬
‪‬
‪割と頑張ってんな‬
They've worked pretty hard.
Yeah...
‪ですね～‬
‪でも ぼっちちゃん…‬
But Bocchi-chan...
Our esteemed bassist, Ryo Yamada,
‪ベースの山田リョウいわく‬
‪ん？‬
told me that any MCing I did for
Kessoku Band would be a flop,
‪結束バンドは‬
‪ＭＣが つまらないそうでして‬
and at first I thought, "How dare you!"
‪“どの口が？”って思うんですけど‬
But until I learn to be
entertaining with this stuff,
‪面白いトークできるようになるまで‬
‪ライブ告知だけにしときますね～‬
I figured I'd stick to concert announcements!
‪‬
Of course, I don't actually know
when our next concert'll be...
‪って… まだ‬
‪次のライブの予定はないんですけど‬
‪もし 気になるって人がいたら‬
But if you wanna see more,
just hit up our vocalist, Kita-chan,
‪ボーカルの喜多ちゃんか…‬
Kita-chan!
‪喜多ちゃ～ん！‬
or our guitarist, Bo—
Hitori Gotoh, when you can!
‪ギターの ぼっ… あっ‬
‪後藤&lrm;ひとりちゃんに‬
‪今度 声かけてください！‬
‪‬
‪わあ～‬
Hitori-chan!
‪ひとりちゃ～ん！‬
Anyway, let's move on to the next song!
‪それじゃ 次の曲 いこっか‬
Right!
‪はい！‬
Please lend us your ears!
‪それでは聴いてください‬
Our next song is
"To Become a Constellation..."!
‪２曲目で“星座になれたら”‬
‪あっ…‬
‪‬
‪♪ もうすぐ時計は６時‬
The time's almost six
‪♪ もうそこに一番星‬
The evening star's already out there
Walking home, stepping on shadows
‪♪ 影を踏んで‬
‪♪ 夜に紛れたくなる帰り道‬
I'm hoping to blend into the night
‪やっぱり おかしい‬
Yeah, something's not right.
Lucky you, lucky you
It's been fine this whole time,
‪昨日まで なんともなかったのに‬
Must be nice to have everyone love you
‪１･２弦のチューニングが‬
‪異常に合わない‬
but now I can't get the E string in tune...
"No, I've always been alone."
‪♪ 「いいや　僕は‬
‪　　　　　　　ずっと一人きりさ」‬
If only I could become
a constellation with you...
‪♪ 君と集まって　星座になれたら‬
On a night of falling stars,
I make that moment's wish
‪♪ 星降る夜…‬
The E string!
‪１弦が！‬
Not good...
‪マズい！　せめて‬
‪２弦のチューニングだけでも…‬
But if I can at least get
the B string in tune...
A sparkling, twinkling,
trembling signal up high
‪あっ ペグが故障してる！‬
The peg's broken!
She can't use the B string now.
‪あれじゃ‬
‪２弦も使いものにならない‬
‪これじゃ ソロ 無理だぞ‬
She won't be able to do her solo.
If only I could become
a constellation with you...
What'll I do?
‪‬
‪どうしよう… もうすぐソロが来る‬
My solo's coming up...
The kind that people point to in the sky
If our big culture festival performance
fails because I had equipment trouble...
‪せっかくの文化祭ライブが‬
‪私の機材トラブルで台なしに‬
Don't let these lines
that link us come undone
‪どうしよう どうしよう…‬
What do I do?
What do I do, what do I do,
what do I do, what do I do?!
‪どうしよう どうしよう‬
‪どうしよう！‬
No matter how brightly I shine
‪♪ 僕がどんなに　&lrm;眩&lrm;しくても‬
Kita-san...
‪喜多さん…‬
‪打ち合わせしてないのにアドリブ！‬
She's ad-libbing completely on the fly!
‪みんなに見せてよ‬
I'm going to make sure everyone can see...
how amazingly cool Gotoh-san really is!
‪本当は後藤さんは すごく‬
‪かっこいいんだってところを‬
‪‬
What's their guitarist doing?
‪あのギター 何やってんだ？‬
‪‬
‪よく分かんねえけど スゲえ！‬
Dunno, but it's pretty awesome!
Who whips out the bottleneck
playing at a time like this?
‪この土壇場でボトルネック奏法とか‬
‪普通やるか？‬
Now it won't matter
if she's a little out of tune!
‪あれならチューニング‬
‪ズレてても関係ないもんね‬
We met each other, so far away
‪♪ &lrm;遥&lrm;か&lrm;彼方‬
‪　　　僕らは出会ってしまった‬
And because it's our karma,
we'll meet again and again
‪♪ カルマだから‬
‪　　　何度も出会ってしまうよ‬
In the gaps between the clouds
‪♪ 雲の隙間で‬
‪♪ 君と集まって　星座になれたら‬
If only I could become
a constellation with you...
‪♪ 夜広げて　描こう絵空事‬
As night falls, I dream that unlikely dream
Not quite a full moon
‪♪ 暗闇を照らすような‬
‪　　　　満月じゃなくても‬
But still lighting up the dark
I want to become a constellation with you
‪♪ だから集まって‬
‪　　　星座になりたい‬
The kind that puts out many-colored light
‪♪ 色とりどりの光　放つような‬
I won't let these lines
that link us come undone
‪♪ つないだ線　&lrm;解&lrm;かないよ‬
No matter how brightly you shine
‪♪ 君がどんなに　眩しくても‬
‪‬
‪ああ～ えっと…‬
Well... I wasn't going to
say anything before our last song,
‪ホントは続けて‬
‪最後の曲 いくところなんですけど‬
but please let me say one thing!
‪これだけ言わせてください！‬
Thanks so much for having us today!
‪今日は本当に ありがと～！‬
‪‬
We're gonna try our best
to become so good,
‪‬
‪この日のライブを みんなが将来‬
that one day you'll brag
about having seen us here!
‪自慢できるくらいのバンドに‬
‪なりま～す！‬
Awesome!
‪‬
‪いいぞ～！‬
Budokan-bound!
‪武道館 行っちゃえ～！‬
You were great, Whatever-san!
‪ご… なんとかさんも‬
‪よかったぞ！‬
‪あっ‬
‪アハッ‬
You did good
even when your string broke!
‪‬
‪弦 切れたのに頑張ったね！‬
‪あ…‬
Hey, Gotoh-san!
‪ほら 後藤さん‬
‪ひと言くらい何か言わなきゃ‬
Looks like you've gotta say something!
‪えっ？‬
‪フフッ‬
‪ああ あっ うっ…‬
P-People with social anxiety can't talk
without a pre-arranged script!
‪コ… コミュ症は‬
‪事前に台本作っとかないと‬
‪しゃべれないのに‬
Go! Go!
Hitori
If you put me in this unplanned situation...
‪予想外のフリされたら…‬
‪‬
Say something funny. Something funny.
‪何か面白いこと 何か面白いこと‬
‪何か…‬
Something... Something... funny...
‪何か… 面白いこと…‬
Gotoh-san?
‪後藤さん？‬
‪ヘヘッ ヘヘヘ‬
‪あっ…‬
‪ん？‬
‪えっ？‬
‪‬
Kessoku Band
Gotoh-san?!
‪きゃ～！‬
‪後藤さん！‬
You okay, Bocchi-chan?!
Someone call a teacher!
‪‬
‪ぼっちちゃん 大丈夫？‬
You're a legendary rock star!
‪‬
‪お前は伝説のロックスターだ‬
‪ハハハッ‬
‪あ～ ぼっちちゃん 最高！‬
Bocchi-chan rocks!
At least show a little concern!
‪少しは心配しろ！‬
Seriously!
‪ホントだよ！‬
Someone bring a stretcher!
‪担架 持ってこい！‬
Hitori! You okay?!
‪ひとり！　大丈夫か？‬
I'm sorry about my sister.
‪‬
‪うちのお姉ちゃんが すみません‬
‪ああ～ いえいえ‬
H-Hey, it's fine!
‪プププッ‬
‪ああ…‬
‪終わった…‬
It's all over.
Are you all right, Gotoh-san?
‪‬
‪後藤さん 大丈夫？　目 覚めた？‬
Are you conscious?
Y-Yeah...
‪あ… はい‬
Thank goodness.
‪よかった～‬
Looks like it wasn't too bad.
‪ケガも大したことないみたい‬
Um...
‪あの…‬
‪ん？‬
I'm really sorry I ruined everything.
‪台なしにしちゃって‬
‪本当に すみませんでした‬
After all you did...
‪せっかくの…‬
Actually, I think people liked it even more.
‪ううん　なぜか‬
‪逆に盛り上がってたかも‬
‪えっ？‬
Um... Where are the others?
‪あっ 虹夏ちゃんたちは？‬
They're cleaning up now.
‪今 片づけ中‬
They said we'd have an after-party
if you were feeling well enough.
‪後藤さん大丈夫なら‬
‪このあと打ち上げ行こうって‬
But if you aren't, we can save it for later.
‪でも 無理そうなら また今度に‬
‪あっ はい…‬
R-Right...
Oh, that was a surprise.
‪あっ 驚きました‬
‪ん？‬
Kita-san. You got so good so fast.
‪喜多さん‬
‪いつの間にか上手になってて‬
‪あ…‬
Only for rhythm, of course.
‪バッキングだけだけどね‬
Um...
‪えっと…‬
I can't do the kind of playing
that really draws people in.
‪私は‬
‪人を惹きつけられるような演奏は‬
‪できない‬
‪え？‬
But I seem to be pretty good
at the give-and-take with you guys.
‪けど みんなと‬
‪合わせるのは得意みたいだから‬
I'm gonna keep working on my playing,
so please keep teaching me.
‪これからも もっと‬
‪ギター頑張るから 教えてね‬
‪後藤さ…‬
Gotoh-sa—
Hitori-chan.
‪ひとりちゃん‬
‪あっ え… あっ はい！‬
R-Right!
Okay, I'm off!
‪じゃあ 先 行くね‬
‪準備できたら来てね‬
Come by when you're ready!
‪あ… はい‬
R-Right...
‪‬
‪あ…‬
I'm going to become good enough
to support Hitori-chan.
‪私 ひとりちゃんを‬
‪支えていけるようになるね‬
The 31st Annual Shuka High School
Culture Festival will now come to an end.
‪これにて…‬
After-party! After-party!
‪打ち上げ 打ち上げ♪‬
‪ぼっちちゃん 大丈夫かな‬
I hope Bocchi-chan's okay...
‪文化祭を終了します‬
Area ahead
off limits
Hey, it's the stage diver.
‪あっ ダイブの人‬
‪うあっ！‬
Oh, the crazy rocker chick?
‪‬
‪ああ ロックなヤベえヤツか‬
Some day...
‪いつか…‬
Some day, I will quit high school!
‪いつか 高校やめてやる！‬
Forgive me, Father!
‪お父さん ごめんなさい‬
‪‬
What're you doing, Sis?
‪お姉ちゃん何してるの？‬
‪ワン ワン！‬
I broke the guitar Dad lent me
while we were playing!
‪‬
‪お父さんから借りたギター‬
‪ライブで壊してしまいました‬
P-Please, get up! I'm really not mad!
‪か… 顔 上げて！‬
‪お父さん 全然 怒ってないから‬
‪ねっ？‬
Please?
‪ペグが壊れただけだろ？‬
‪そんな心配しなくていいよ‬
It's just a broken peg, right?
It's really not that big a deal.
But...
‪でも…‬
Plus, it was pretty rad the way
you broke it in the middle of the concert!
‪‬
‪それに ライブ中に壊すなんて‬
‪なんか お父さん興奮しちゃうな～‬
‪え？‬
Nowadays, they sell guitars
designed to break.
‪今は“破壊専用ギター”‬
‪ってやつも売ってるらしいし‬
You should use one of those in your next gig!
‪今度のライブで してくれよ‬
‪娘を どの方向に‬
‪持っていきたいんだ…‬
What kind of daughter
are you trying to raise?
Anyway, this is probably a good opportunity
for you to buy your own guitar.
‪これも いい機会だし‬
‪ひとりも自分のギター‬
Play with me, Dad!
‪買ってみたらどうだ？‬
‪遊んで～‬
What a good idea!
‪あっ それいいじゃない‬
‪ねえ お父さ～ん‬
C'mon, Dad!
That way, if you hit an issue like this again,
you can deal with it right away.
‪‬
‪今回みたいにトラブったときに‬
‪すぐ対応できるしさ‬
But... Even though I do have a job,
all the money goes to my quotas.
‪‬
‪いや でも バイトはしてるけど‬
‪ライブのノルマで消えるから‬
‪そんなお金は…‬
I can't afford...
No worries!
‪大丈夫！‬
‪あ…‬
You've got money!
‪お金ならある！‬
‪ハッ！‬
‪なな… 何？　この大金‬
‪お父さん まさか闇営業…‬
Wh-Where'd it all come from?
Dad, are you involved
in some shady dealings?!
‪は？‬
I c-can't accept your dirty money!
‪ここ… こんな黒いお金‬
‪受け取れないよ‬
We're not that badly off!
‪‬
‪うちは そんな切迫してないよ！‬
That's money you earned from
advertisements on your videos.
‪それはね ひとりの‬
‪動画広告収入で得たお金なのよ‬
‪え？‬
See, if a video gets enough views,
they pay you.
‪一定の再生数があると‬
‪お金がもらえるんだよ‬
‪えっ…‬
Did you forget the video site account
you use is a family account?
‪動画サイトのアカウント‬
‪家族共有になってたの忘れてただろ‬
You mean, my videos...
‪じゃあ 私の動画…‬
We know all about 'em!
‪もちろん知ってるよ‬
‪ギターヒーローだろ？‬
guitarhero, right?
They've been racking up the views,
so I monetized 'em in secret.
‪再生数 結構あったから‬
‪お父さん こっそり‬
‪広告付けておいたんだ‬
How'd my girl get so good?!
‪うちの娘 うますぎ！‬
I figured you'd need the money eventually.
‪いつか こうやって‬
‪必要になるときが来るかもと思って‬
And it's been amazing
to see you work so hard
‪ひとりが練習 頑張って‬
and get better and better at the guitar.
‪演奏 どんどん‬
‪うまくなってく過程が見れたのは‬
‪本当に うれしかったなあ‬
Right, dear?
‪ねっ？　お母さん‬
Yes.
‪ええ‬
I don't know much about music,
‪お母さん 音楽は‬
‪よく分からないけど‬
but I do think you're amazing at it!
‪上手だなって思ったよ‬
Dad... Mom...
‪お父さん お母さん…‬
guitarhero
This song's been a big hit
with all my friends lately!
I sing this all the time at karaoke!
The chorus gets everyone sooo hype!
o(^v^)o
My boyfriend loves this song!
まあ それに比例して
Of course, it's balanced out
虚言が達者に
なってく過程は
by my sadness at seeing you
get better and better at lying...
父さん 悲しかったけど
Barf!
‪ゲロゲロ～！‬
There's 300,000 yen here.
‪30万ある…‬
I never imagined getting such a windfall.
‪まさか こんな‬
‪棚ぼた展開が起こるなんて‬
If I buy a guitar that costs 100k,
I'll have 200k left...
‪10万前後のギターを買ったとして‬
‪残り20万…‬
And if I put that all to quota costs,
‪この残りをノルマに当てれば‬
‪２年近くはバイトしなくても‬
‪ライブできる！‬
I could play for almost two years
without having to work a normal job!
‪よし！　バイト辞めよう！‬
Yes!
I'm totally quitting!
Bocchi-chan's been unusually chipper today.
‪今日の ぼっちちゃん‬
‪ずっとキラキラしてるんだけど‬
And she bows at me
every time we make eye contact.
‪目が合うたび‬
‪おじぎしてくるんですよね‬
‪あっ‬
‪アハハ…‬
The thought of quitting my job fills me
with a mysterious and overwhelming power!
‪‬
‪バイト辞めれると思ったら‬
‪謎のパワーが無限に湧いてくる！‬
Time to talk to the manager now!
‪早速 店長さんに言いに行こう！‬
‪はあああ～っ！‬
‪超スーパーぼっちちゃん？‬
Ultra super Bocchi-chan?
‪あ？　バイトがなんだって？‬
What's this about your job?
I... W-Well... S-See...
‪あっ えっと その…‬
I'll continue to work my hardest
and most earnestly at it.
‪これからも誠心誠意‬
‪心血注いで仕事 頑張ります…‬
What's with the sudden
declaration of commitment?
‪なんで突然の決意表明？‬
There's nothing harder than
declaring you're gonna quit a job.
‪バイト辞めるのは‬
‪切り出すのが一番大変なんだ‬
Maybe I should ghost them...
‪バックレ…‬
But they do know where I li—
Uh, I mean, I don't want to put them out...
‪いやいや 住所 押さえられてるし…‬
‪じゃなくて みんなに迷惑が‬
Bocchi-chan!
‪ぼっちちゃ～ん‬
‪今日 楽器屋さん行くんでしょ？‬
You're going to the
music shop today, right?
‪ハッ！‬
Maybe if I buy an instrument
for the manager, she'll let me quit!
‪何か店長さんに献上したら‬
‪辞めさせてもらえるかも‬
‪今なら お金 たくさんあるし！‬
I've got lots of money now, after all!
Bocchi-chan?
‪あっ あの…‬
H-Hey... Could you ask the manager
if there's anything she wants?
‪店長さんの今 欲しいもの‬
‪聞いてきてもらえますか？‬
Bocchi-chan asked that.
‪って ぼっちちゃんが‬
Since your birthday's coming up,
maybe she's talking about a present?
‪お姉ちゃん 誕生日 近いし‬
‪プレゼントかな？‬
I don't want anything.
‪特にない‬
She says no thanks!
‪“いらねえ”だって‬
‪うがっ‬
I'm finished.
‪終わった…‬
‪ぼっち 私は‬
Bocchi. I'd like a Dingwall and new Le Fay
headless and a Darkglass amp head.
‪Dingwall&lrm;とル･フェの‬
‪新作ヘッドレス‬
‪それと Darkglassの‬
‪アンプヘッドが欲しい‬
‪‬
‪皆さ～ん 楽器屋さん行きますよ～‬
We're heading to the music shop, everyone!
Let's la go!
‪レッツラゴー！‬
Bocchi-chan's really nice.
Have fun!
‪いってらっしゃ～い‬
‪ぼっちちゃん 優しい…‬
But I prefer my presents to be a surprise.
‪‬
‪でも 私はサプライズ派なんだ‬
‪ん？‬
Funder
Guitars
Internet
Electric
Guitar
Shop
Musical
Instruments
If you wanna buy an instrument,
you gotta go to Ochanomizu!
‪楽器屋さんといったら‬
‪やっぱ御茶ノ水だよね～‬
‪ねえ ひとりちゃん‬
Hey, Hitori-chan!
‪なんでこんなに‬
‪楽器屋さんあるんだろうね？‬
Do you know why there are
so many music shops here?
Well, you see...
‪そ　れ　は！‬
The music business flourished here
due to it playing host in the Meiji Period
‪明治時代に‬
‪日本で最も古い歴史を誇る‬
‪プロオーケストラが結成されてから‬
to Japan's oldest professional orchestra,
leading to the formation
‪都内で音楽活動が盛んになって‬
of now-legacy stores in Ochanomizu
like Shimokura Music,
‪そのころ御茶ノ水で‬
‪今では老舗と呼ばれる下倉楽器‬
‪イシバシ楽器が出来て‬
‪うんぬんかんぬん…‬
Ishibashi Music, and etc etc,
blah blah, yada yada...
I bet we'll be seeing a lot of this today.
‪今日一日 シュバってきそう‬
Let's go in here! It's got a great selection!
‪‬
‪ここ入ろう！　品ぞろえいいし‬
I'd really rather not.
‪入りたくないな…‬
I was gonna just buy one online, but...
‪本当はネットで注文しちゃおう‬
‪って思ってたけど‬
Ordering online is fine and all,
‪通販サイトもいいけど‬
‪実際に触ってみて選ぶのがいいよ‬
but you really oughta handle
a guitar before you buy it!
R-Right...
‪あっ はい‬
Music store owners are scary,
and if one were to start talking to me...
‪‬
‪楽器屋って店員さん怖そうだし‬
‪もし話しかけられたりしたら…‬
You like that guitar?
You got good taste, dearie.
‪お前 このギター選ぶとか‬
‪なかなかのセンスじゃん？‬
‪えっ…‬
You like Western music?
‪洋楽とか聴く？‬
‪ああ 聴かない？　殺すぞ！‬
Wait, you don't?!
Time to die!
‪あっ あああ～‬
‪イ… イヤホンつけて‬
‪ノッてるふりしてれば‬
If I put on headphones
like I'm listening to music,
maybe no one will talk to me!
‪話しかけてこないはず‬
M-Manager! A major headbanger
has entered the store!
‪て… 店長‬
‪すごいヘドバン少女が‬
‪来店してきました！‬
Must be a hardcore metal fan!
‪‬
‪コアなメタルファンに違いない！‬
‪ハア ハア…‬
‪お客様！‬
Ma'am! The heavy metal guitars
are on the second floor!
‪メタル志向のギターを‬
‪お探しなら２階の…‬
‪あっ えっ？‬
‪‬
‪あっ このストラップ かわいい！‬
What a cute strap!
‪この色とか喜多ちゃんの‬
‪ギターに似合うんじゃない？‬
This color would look great
with your guitar, Kita-chan!
‪わあ～ ピックって‬
‪こんなに種類あるんですね‬
Look at all the kinds of picks!
Maybe I'll turn some into earrings!
‪イヤリングに加工しちゃおうかな‬
What a great idea!
‪いいんじゃない？‬
What's the matter, ma'am? Ma'am?
‪お客様 どうされ…‬
Can we stop by a hobby shop after this?
‪このあと‬
‪ハンドメイドショップ行きません？‬
Plus, I checked in advance and found out
there's a nice café nearby!
‪あっ あと さっき調べたら‬
‪お客様～！‬
Ma'am?!
‪‬
‪近くに いい感じのカフェも…‬
Look at the damn instruments.
‪楽器 見ろや‬
Excuse me.
‪すみません このベースって‬
‪試奏できたりしますか？‬
Can I try out this bass?
Go ahead.
‪大丈夫ですよ‬
You're buying another, Senpai?
‪先輩 また買うんですか？‬
No.
‪別に‬
I just like how it looks,
so I'd like to play it a bit.
‪ちょっと気になるから‬
‪軽く弾きたいだけ‬
Ah, is slapping okay?
‪あっ スラップしていいですか？‬
Yes, that's fine.
‪はい いいですよ‬
Like this.
‪あっ！　こいつ まさか！‬
‪これなんですけど‬
Is she going to do that?
‪‬
‪ハッ！‬
‪わあ～‬
‪おお～‬
‪まあ すごい…‬
Amazing.
I didn't even go that hard.
‪て… 適当に弾いた… だけだけど‬
What a great bass!
‪すごい いいベース‬
When you go all-out but act smug about it!
‪‬
‪試奏で本気出してドヤるヤツだ！‬
Not that I mind.
‪別にいいけどさ‬
‪何？　郁代‬
‪ん？‬
What is it, Ikuyo?
You like that guitar?
‪そのギター気になるの？‬
No, it's not like that...
‪えっ？‬
‪あっ いや そういうわけでは…‬
‪ん？‬
‪私には リョウ先輩から‬
‪お借りしてるギターがありますので‬
I've still got the guitar
you lent me, after all!
‪‬
‪ギターは何本あっても困らない‬
You can never have too many guitars.
They're all having so much fun.
‪みんな楽しそうでいいな～‬
‪あっ…‬
‪これが漫画でよく見る‬
‪ドラマー孤独問題か‬
Is this the lonely drummer thing
I see in manga all the time?
M-Maybe I'll buy a guitar and a bass myself!
‪あっ あたしもギターとベース‬
‪か… 買っちゃおうかな～‬
‪ええ～？‬
Just to play, darn it!
‪普通に弾く用でだよ！‬
I see. Were you feeling lonely?
‪‬
‪そうか さみしかったのか‬
Let's hit up a drum shop next time!
‪‬
‪今度はドラム専門店 行こうね！‬
There's one in Akiba.
‪アキバにあるから‬
This one's cool...
‪これ かっこいい…‬
Yamaha's pretty great, huh?
‪‬
‪YAMAHA&lrm;さん いいですよね～‬
‪あひい～！‬
That one's custom-made, too.
‪それ 特注仕様なんですよ‬
‪手ごろな価格ですけど‬
‪すごくいいギターですよ‬
It's a really great guitar,
especially for the price!
Would you like to try it out?
‪あ… よかったら‬
‪試奏なされますか？‬
‪あっ いや えっと…‬
Um... Um...
‪初めてのギターなら‬
If it's your first guitar, you might
want shielding and a mini amp!
‪シールドとミニアンプも‬
‪そろえたほうがいいですよ‬
I...
‪あっ うっ…‬
‪うぐっ…‬
I'll take the lot.
‪買います…‬
You already have that stuff, Bocchi-chan!
‪‬
‪ぼっちちゃん もう持ってるでしょ‬
Oh, you already play? I'm so sorry!
‪あっ 経験者の方でしたか！‬
‪失礼しました‬
Hey, that's okay.
‪‬
‪あっ いえいえ 大丈夫ですよ‬
Her guitar broke recently,
‪この子のギターが‬
‪最近 壊れちゃって‬
so she's looking for a replacement.
‪今日は代替機を探しに来たんです‬
‪ね？　ひとりちゃん‬
Right, Hitori-chan?
‪あん あん‬
Lots of people have multiples nowadays.
Even students!
‪今どき 学生さんでも‬
‪何本も持ってる方‬
‪いらっしゃいますからね‬
Oh, really?
‪そうなんですね～‬
You like this guitar, Hitori-chan?
‪このギター 気に入った？‬
‪ひとりちゃん‬
‪あん‬
Right. Right.
‪うん　うん…‬
She'll take this guitar, please!
‪このギターにするそうです‬
Right, Hitori-chan?
‪ね？　ひとりちゃん‬
Thank you so much!
‪ありがとうございます！‬
Bocchi's like a ventriloquist dummy.
‪‬
‪ぼっち 腹話術の人形みたい‬
I thought she'd matured a lot lately,
‪‬
‪最近 成長したと思ったけど‬
But I guess she still
has some ways to go.
‪こういうとこ まだまだだな‬
I'm so glad.
‪よかった～‬
I've been doing checks and
maintenance on this guitar myself.
‪このギター 私が検品して‬
‪メンテナンスもしてたんです‬
‪えっ？‬
It's really well made. I like it a lot.
‪すごく作りが良くて‬
‪私も お気に入りで‬
I'm sure the guitar's happy
that it's going with you, too.
‪このギターも お客様に選ばれて‬
‪うれしいと思いますよ‬
Thank you for coming!
‪お買い上げ‬
‪ありがとうございました！‬
‪あっ あ…‬
‪ん？‬
Th-Thank you for having me!
‪‬
‪ありがとうございました！‬
M-Ma'am?!
‪‬
‪お客様？　ギター忘れてますよ！‬
You forgot your guitar!
‪どんだけ帰りたかったの‬
How desperate was she to get out of here?
Here!
‪はい‬
The manager wants you
to come by again some time.
‪店長さん“また お店に‬
‪遊びに来てください”って‬
‪あっ はい　すみません‬
R-Right. Sorry...
I'm really glad you found a good guitar!
‪‬
‪いいギター見つかって よかったね‬
R-Right.
‪あっ はい‬
What now? Wanna grab food first?
‪‬
‪どうする？　なんか食べて帰る？‬
‪あ…‬
We're done.
‪今日は解散‬
‪えっ？‬
Got something else to do?
‪なんか用事？‬
Bocchi. You want to play your guitar
as soon as possible, right?
‪ぼっち‬
‪早くギター弾きたいでしょ？‬
‪あっ‬
‪ああ～‬
‪ハッ！‬
Hey! Stop having a telepathic
connection, you two!
‪もう～ また２人だけ‬
‪通じ合う感じ出してる！‬
‪まあまあ 落ち着いて‬
Hey, it's no big deal.
I know!
‪あっ そうだ！‬
‪じゃあ 今からスタジオ借りて‬
Want to rent a studio
and try out your new guitar?
‪ひとりちゃんのギター‬
‪お披露目会します？‬
Ah, I'd rather not...
‪いや それは ちょっと…‬
We'll all get to practice
together tomorrow, anyway.
‪‬
‪まあ 明日 みんなで練習するしね‬
We'll save the fun for then!
‪そんときのお楽しみにしよ～‬
R-Right.
‪は… はい‬
The culture festival is behind us.
‪文化祭も終わったし‬
We'd better start thinking
about our next concert, right?
‪次のライブのこととか‬
‪いろいろ考えないとね～‬
That's right!
‪ですね！‬
Write us lots of new songs, Ryo!
‪リョウも新曲よろしく！‬
Just waiting for inspiration to strike.
‪こればっかりは‬
‪インスピレーション待ち‬
‪私に できることあったら‬
‪なんでも言ってくださいね‬
Let me know if there's anything I can do!
‪なんでも？‬
Anything?
‪喜多ちゃ～ん‬
Kita-chan! Don't say that to Ryo
unless you're ready to follow through!
‪リョウに気安く‬
‪そういうこと言っちゃダメだよ‬
You can start by treating me to gyudon.
‪フフッ‬
‪じゃあ 早速だけど‬
‪牛丼おごって‬
‪お姉ちゃ～ん！‬
Sis! Hurry up or you'll be late!
‪早くしないと遅刻するよ～‬
‪はあ～‬
‪ウッ ウヘヘ　か… かっこいい‬
A-Awesome...
‪あっ‬
‪ハッ！‬
I'm s-sorry! I haven't f-forgotten you!
‪あっ ご… ごめんなさい！‬
‪き… 君のことも忘れてないよ！‬
Forgive me!
‪ゆ… 許して～！‬
She's at it again.
‪あの子 また…‬
‪ああ…‬
‪クウ～ン‬
Be back later.
‪いってきます‬
My First
‪‬
‪今日もバイトか～‬
Another day at the job.
Illustration by Aki Hamaji
Thanks for watching!
Thank you!
センキュー！